let problem = Math.floor(Math.random() * 5);
let quizData = [
    {
        question: "is a segment that connects the midpoints of two sides.",
        a: "Median",
        b: "Angle Bisector",
        c: "Midsegment",
        d: "Altitude",
        e: "Perpendicular bisector",
        correct: "c",
    },
    {
        question: "is a segment that bisects an angle.",
        a: "Perpendicular bisector",
        b: "Midsegment",
        c: "Altitude",
        d: "Angle bisector",
        e: "Median",
        correct: "d",
    },
    {
        question: "is a segment that bisects a side and is perpendicular to that side.",
        a: "Altitude",
        b: "Angle Bisector",
        c: "Perpendicular bisector",
        d: "Median",
        e: "Midsegment",
        correct: "c",
    },
    {
        question: "is a segment that connects a vertex to the midpoints of the opposite side.",
        a: "Midsegment",
        b: "Median",
        c: "Altitude",
        d: "Perpendicular Bisector",
        e: "Angle bisector",
        correct: "b",
    },
    {
        question: "is a segment from a vertex, perpendicular to the opposite side.",
        a: "Altitude",
        b: "Perpendicular Bisector",
        c: "Midsegment",
        d: "Median",
        e: "Angle bisector",
        correct: "a",
    },

]

if (problem == 1){
    quizData = [
        {
            question: "is a segment that connects the midpoints of two sides.",
            a: "Angle Bisector",
            b: "Median",
            c: "Perpendicular Bisector",
            d: "Midsegment",
            e: "Altitude",
            correct: "d",
        },
        {
            question: "is a segment that bisects an angle.",
            a: "Midsegment",
            b: "Perpendicular Bisector",
            c: "Median",
            d: "Altitude",
            e: "Angle Bisector",
            correct: "e",
        },
        {
            question: "is a segment that bisects a side and is perpendicular to that side.",
            a: "Angle Bisector",
            b: "Altitude",
            c: "Midsegment",
            d: "Perpendicular Bisector",
            e: "Meidan",
            correct: "d",
        },
        {
            question: "is a segment that connects a vertex to the midpoints of the opposite side.",
            a: "Median",
            b: "Midsegment",
            c: "Angle Bisector",
            d: "Altitude",
            e: "Perpendicular Bisector",
            correct: "a",
        },
        {
            question: "is a segment from a vertex, perpendicular to the opposite side.",
            a: "Perpendicular Bisector",
            b: "Altitude",
            c: "Angle Bisector",
            d: "Midsegment",
            e: "Median",
            correct: "b",
        },
    
    ];
}
else if (problem == 2){
    quizData = [
        {
            question: "is a segment that connects the midpoints of two sides.",
            a: "Angle Bisector",
            b: "Midsegment",
            c: "Median",
            d: "Perpendicular",
            e: "Altitude",
            correct: "b",
        },
        {
            question: "is a segment that bisects an angle.",
            a: "Midsegment",
            b: "Altitude",
            c: "Perpendicular bisector",
            d: "Median",
            e: "Angle Bisector",
            correct: "e",
        },
        {
            question: "is a segment that bisects a side and is perpendicular to that side.",
            a: "Angle Bisector",
            b: "Perpendicular Bisector",
            c: "Altitude",
            d: "Midsegment",
            e: "Median",
            correct: "b",
        },
        {
            question: "is a segment that connects a vertex to the midpoints of the opposite side.",
            a: "Median",
            b: "Altitude",
            c: "Midsegment",
            d: "Angle bisector",
            e: "Perpendicular Bisector",
            correct: "a",
        },
        {
            question: "is a segment from a vertex, perpendicular to the opposite side.",
            a: "Altitude",
            b: "Perpendicular Bisector",
            c: "Midsegment",
            d: "Median",
            e: "Angle bisector",
            correct: "a",
        },
    
    ];
}

else if (problem == 3){
    quizData = [
        {
            question: "is a segment that connects the midpoints of two sides.",
            a: "Midsegment",
            b: "Altitude",
            c: "Median",
            d: "Angle Bisector",
            e: "Perpendicular bisector",
            correct: "a",
        },
        {
            question: "is a segment that bisects an angle.",
            a: "Altitude",
            b: "Angle Bisector",
            c: "Perpendicular Bisector", 
            d: "Midsegment",
            e: "Median",
            correct: "b",
        },
        {
            question: "is a segment that bisects a side and is perpendicular to that side.",
            a: "Perpendicular bisector",
            b: "Median",
            c: "Altitude",
            d: "Angle Bisector",
            e: "Midsegment",
            correct: "a",
        },
        {
            question: "is a segment that connects a vertex to the midpoints of the opposite side.",
            a: "Altitude",
            b: "Perpendicular Bisector",
            c: "Midsegment",
            d: "Median",
            e: "Angle bisector",
            correct: "d",
        },
        {
            question: "is a segment from a vertex, perpendicular to the opposite side.",
            a: "Midsegment",
            b: "Median",
            c: "Altitude",
            d: "Perpendicular Bisector",
            e: "Angle bisector",
            correct: "c",
        },
    
    ];
}

else if (problem == 4){
    quizData = [
        {
            question: "is a segment that connects the midpoints of two sides.",
            a: "Median",
            b: "Altitude",
            c: "Perpendicular Bisector",
            d: "Angle Bisector",
            e: "Midsegment",
            correct: "e",
        },
        {
            question: "is a segment that bisects an angle.",
            a: "Perpendicular bisector",
            b: "Angle Bisector",
            c: "Median",
            d: "Midsegment",
            e: "Altitude",
            correct: "b",
        },
        {
            question: "is a segment that bisects a side and is perpendicular to that side.",
            a: "Altitude",
            b: "Median",
            c: "Midsegment",
            d: "Angle Bisector",
            e: "Perpendicular Bisector",
            correct: "e",
        },
        {
            question: "is a segment that connects a vertex to the midpoints of the opposite side.",
            a: "Midsegment",
            b: "Median",
            c: "Altitude",
            d: "Perpendicular Bisector",
            e: "Angle bisector",
            correct: "b",
        },
        {
            question: "is a segment from a vertex, perpendicular to the opposite side.",
            a: "Altitude",
            b: "Median",
            c: "Angle Bisector",
            d: "Perpendicular Bisector",
            e: "Midsegment",
            correct: "a",
        },
    
    ];
}

else if (problem == 5){
    quizData = [
        {
            question: "is a segment that connects the midpoints of two sides.",
            a: "Perpendicular Bisector",
            b: "Altitude",
            c: "Median",
            d: "Angle Bisector",
            e: "Midsegment",
            correct: "e",
        },
        {
            question: "is a segment that bisects an angle.",
            a: "Median",
            b: "Angle bisector",
            c: "Perpendicular bisector",
            d: "Midsegment",
            e: "Altitude",
            correct: "b",
        },
        {
            question: "is a segment that bisects a side and is perpendicular to that side.",
            a: "Midsegment",
            b: "Median",
            c: "Altitude",
            d: "Angle Bisector",
            e: "Perpendicular bisector",
            correct: "e",
        },
        {
            question: "is a segment that connects a vertex to the midpoints of the opposite side.",
            a: "Angle bisector",
            b: "Perpendicular Bisector",
            c: "Midsegment",
            d: "Median",
            e: "Altitude",
            correct: "d",
        },
        {
            question: "is a segment from a vertex, perpendicular to the opposite side.",
            a: "Angle Bisector",
            b: "Median",
            c: "Altitude",
            d: "Perpendicular Bisector",
            e: "Midsegment",
            correct: "c",
        },
    
    ];
}


function shuffle(array) {
    let currentIndex = array.length, randomIndex;

    //While there remain elements to shuffle…
    while (currentIndex != 0) {
        //Pick a remaining element…
        randomIndex = Math.floor(Math.random() * currentIndex);
        currentIndex--;
        //And swap it with the current element. 
        [array[currentIndex], array[randomIndex]] = [array[randomIndex], array[currentIndex]];
    }
    return array;
}

const quizeData = shuffle(quizData)


const quiz= document.getElementById('quiz')
const answerEls = document.querySelectorAll('.answer')
const questionEl = document.getElementById('question')
const a_text = document.getElementById('a_text')
const b_text = document.getElementById('b_text')
const c_text = document.getElementById('c_text')
const d_text = document.getElementById('d_text')
const e_text = document.getElementById('e_text')
const submitBtn = document.getElementById('submit')


let currentQuiz = 0
let score = 0



loadQuiz()

function loadQuiz() {

    deselectAnswers()

    const currentQuizData = quizeData[currentQuiz]

    questionEl.innerText = currentQuizData.question
    a_text.innerText = currentQuizData.a
    b_text.innerText = currentQuizData.b
    c_text.innerText = currentQuizData.c
    d_text.innerText = currentQuizData.d
    e_text.innerText = currentQuizData.e
}

function deselectAnswers() {
    answerEls.forEach(answerEl => answerEl.checked = false)
}


function getSelected() {
    let answer
    answerEls.forEach(answerEl => {
        if(answerEl.checked) {
            answer = answerEl.id
        }
    })
    return answer
}


submitBtn.addEventListener('click', () => {
    const answer = getSelected()
    if(answer) {
       if(answer === quizData[currentQuiz].correct) {
           score++
       }

       currentQuiz++

       if(currentQuiz < quizData.length) {
           loadQuiz()
       } else {
           quiz.innerHTML = `
           <h2>You answered ${score}/${quizData.length} questions correctly</h2>

           <button onclick="location.reload()">Reload</button>
           `
       }
    }
})